277 Homestead Court Palmyra, PA 17078 January 6, 2014

Attention Human Resources:

Please accept the enclosed resume as an expression of my interest in being a secondary education teacher in social studies at your school district.

As you will note, my enclosed resume shows that I am currently substitute teaching for multiple schools. I am a passionate learner in the field and love to share my knowledge with others. I care deeply for the education of the students, and have vast ways in being able to get the information across. My teaching experience includes lesson development, relaying the lessons effectively, communicating effectively and respectfully with students, assertive discipline techniques, student tutoring and student performance evaluations. I am confident that I can meet the requirements of a social studies teacher through my experiences and contribute in a positive manner to your scholastic objectives.

I would appreciate the opportunity for a personal interview at your convenience. You may contact me at the address and telephone number listed below, or by email at <Mr.AlexShuey@gmail.com>. If you desire further information at this time, I will gladly respond on request. Thank you for your time and attention. I look forward to hearing from you in the near future!

Sincerely,

Alex Shuey

ALEX SHUEY

277 Homestead Court

Palmyra, PA 17078

717-497-5333

Mr.AlexShuey@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

A full time position as a secondary education teacher in social studies.

EDUCATION

 Pennsylvania State University, Capital College, Middletown, PA Bachelor of Secondary Education in Social Studies, May 2013, GPA 3.39

SKILLS

- Computer--Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Prezi, Google Apps, Edmodo
- Lesson Planning, communication
- Hardworking, team player, strong work ethic, quick learner

COURSEWORK

- Field Observation
- Learning Theory and Instructional Procedures
- Social and Cultural Factors in Education
- Teaching Secondary Social Studies
- Addressing the Needs of Special Learners
- Student Teaching

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

SUBSTITUTE TEACHER September 2013 to Present

Derry Township, Milton Hershey and Lower Dauphin School District

Taught in Middle School and High School classrooms, took on daily teaching activities as a Learning Support, Gifted, Special Education, In School Suspension and General Education Teacher.

GETTYSBURG NATIONAL MILITARY PARK 150^{TH} ANNIVERSARY VOLUNTEER July 2013

Gettysburg, PA

Barbra Sanders, Coordinator

Was assigned to the family activities tent in which I informed local visitors about medical

procedures during the Battle of Gettysburg. Worked with all ages, displayed replicated items to show and educate visitors on what the items were used for.

STUDENT TEACHING February 2013 to April 2013

Hershey Middle School, Hershey, PA

Arthur Titzel, Cooperating Teacher

Taught class daily, took on daily responsibilities and activities as a teacher, graded and gave assignments and tutored students. Volunteered for Mini-Thon, the Hershey Middle School dance, the field trip to Gettysburg, Gold Day and organized the 8th grade talent show. Attended teacher inservices, professional development workshops and faculty meetings.

STUDENT FIELD PLACEMENT October 2011 to December 2011

Milton Hershey School, Hershey, PA

Andrew Miller, Cooperating Teacher

Assisted teacher in daily activities for the students. Planned and taught lessons for American History class, graded and gave assignments, and tutored students after school.

PALMYRA AREA HIGH SCHOOL ICE HOCKEY COACH 2010-PRESENT

Certified under USA Hockey, taught the fundamentals of ice hockey, ran practices and coached games. Built characteristics like hard work ethic, teamwork, respect, and communication.

USA HOCKEY REFEREE 2008-2010

Enforced USA Hockey regulations and rules throughout the game. Taught children the basic rules of hockey, in how to play fair and with respect. Refereed numerous games from ages five to twelve.

WORK EXPERIENCE

THE SPA AT THE HOTEL HERSHEY 2011- present

Assisted in daily operations throughout the spa. Interacted professionally and effectively with guests.

HERSHEY CHOCOLATE WORLD 2005-2012

Worked daily in the entertainment department with children. Verbal interaction with children, spread cheer through children of all ages. Worked in costumes, Kiss Works and the Hershey's Really Big 3D Show.

HONORS/AWARDS

Dean's List, completed a High Impact Strategies training that focused on Learning-Focused Schools Strategies.

ACTIVITIES/INTERESTS

Weightlifting, Penn State Ice Hockey 2010-2013, Nature Activities

ALEX SHUEY

277 Homestead Court

Palmyra, PA 17078

717-497-5333

Mr.AlexShuey@gmail.com

Professional References:

Mr. Arthur Titzel 8th grade American Cultures Teacher Hershey Middle School PO Box 898 Hershey, PA 17033 717-730-9809 atitzel@hershey.k12.pa.us

Mrs. Carol Graber
Retired teacher after 29 years, grades 4 to 7
Supervisor of Student Teachers for Penn State University
Shippensburg University and Texas A&M University
11 Banbury Road
Hummelstown, PA 17036
717- 566-6025
Cagraber@verizon.net

Dr. Stacy Winslow Principal of Hershey Middle School Hershey Middle School PO Box 898 Hershey, PA 17033 717-531-2222 ext. 4202 swinslow@hershey.k12.pa.us

Ms. Jeanne Trump Elementary Teacher 5th Grade Union Canal Elem. School 700 Narrows Drive Lebanon, PA 17046 717-270-7227 Jtrump@clsd.k12.pa.us